netlawman.co.uk 2018-10-10

# Privacy Notice For The Net Lawman UK Site

This is the privacy notice of Net Lawman. In this document, "we", "our", or "us" refer to Net Lawman Ltd.

We are company number 2657400 registered in UK.

Our registered office is at St Andrews Castle, 33 St Andrews Street South, Bury St Edmunds, IP33 3PH, United Kingdom.

##  Introduction

  1. This is a notice to inform you of our policy about all information that we record about you. It sets out the conditions under which we may process any information that we collect from you, or that you provide to us. It covers information that could identify you (“personal information”) and information that could not. In the context of the law and this notice, “process” means collect, store, transfer, use or otherwise act on information.
  2. We regret that if there are one or more points below with which you are not happy, your only recourse is to leave our website immediately.
  3. We take seriously the protection of your privacy and confidentiality. We understand that all visitors to our website are entitled to know that their personal data will not be used for any purpose unintended by them, and will not accidentally fall into the hands of a third party.
  4. We undertake to preserve the confidentiality of all information you provide to us, and hope that you reciprocate.
  5. Our policy complies with the Data Protection Act 2018 (Act) accordingly incorporating the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
  6. The law requires us to tell you about your rights and our obligations to you in regards to the processing and control of your personal data. We do this now, by requesting that you read the information provided at www.knowyourprivacyrights.org
  7. Except as set out below, we do not share, or sell, or disclose to a third party, any information collected through our website.

##  The bases on which we process information about you

The law requires us to determine under which of six defined bases we process different categories of your personal information, and to notify you of the basis for each category.

If a basis on which we process your personal information is no longer relevant then we shall immediately stop processing your data.

If the basis changes then if required by law we shall notify you of the change and of any new basis under which we have determined that we can continue to process your information.

###  1\. Information we process because we have a contractual obligation with you

When you create an account on our website, buy a product or service from us, or otherwise agree to our terms and conditions, a contract is formed between you and us.

In order to carry out our obligations under that contract we must process the information you give us. Some of this information may be personal information.

We may use it in order to:

**1.1**    verify your identity for security purposes

**1.2**    sell products to you

**1.3**    provide you with our services

**1.4**    provide you with suggestions and advice on products, services and how to obtain the most from using our website

We process this information on the basis there is a contract between us, or that you have requested we use the information before we enter into a legal contract.

Additionally, we may aggregate this information in a general way and use it to provide class information, for example to monitor our performance with respect to a particular service we provide. If we use it for this purpose, you as an individual will not be personally identifiable.

We shall continue to process this information until the contract between us ends or is terminated by either party under the terms of the contract.

###  2\. Information we process with your consent

Through certain actions when otherwise there is no contractual relationship between us, such as when you browse our website or ask us to provide you more information about our products and services, you provide your consent to us to process information that may be personal information.

Wherever possible, we aim to obtain your explicit consent to process this information, for example, by asking you to agree to our use of cookies.

Sometimes you might give your consent implicitly, such as when you send us a message by e-mail to which you would reasonably expect us to reply.

Except where you have consented to our use of your information for a specific purpose, we do not use your information in any way that would identify you personally. We may aggregate it in a general way and use it to provide class information, for example to monitor the performance of a particular page on our website.

If you have given us explicit permission to do so, we may from time to time pass your name and contact information to selected associates whom we consider may provide services or products you would find useful.

We continue to process your information on this basis until you withdraw your consent or it can be reasonably assumed that your consent no longer exists.

You may withdraw your consent at any time by instructing us [support@netlawman.co.uk](mailto:support@netlawman.co.uk). However, if you do so, you may not be able to use our website or our services further.

###  3\. Information we process because we have a legal obligation

We are subject to the law like everyone else. Sometimes, we must process your information in order to comply with a statutory obligation.

For example, we may be required to give information to legal authorities if they so request or if they have the proper authorisation such as a search warrant or court order.

This may include your personal information.

##  Specific uses of information you provide to us

###  4\. Reviews you post on our website

Our website allows you to post reviews about the product or service you have purchased with a view to that information being read or used by other people.

We do not specifically use this information except to allow it to be displayed on our website.

We do store it, and we reserve a right to use it in the future in any way we decide.

Provided your request is reasonable and there is no legal basis for us to retain it, then at our discretion we may agree to your request to delete your review with your personal information that you have posted. You can make a request by contacting us at [support@netlawman.co.uk](mailto:support@netlawman.co.uk)

###  5\. Information relating to your method of payment

Payment information is never taken by us or transferred to us either through our website or otherwise. Our employees and contractors never have access to it.

At the point of payment, you are transferred to a secure page on the website of SagePay and PayPal. That page may be branded to look like a page on our website, but it is not controlled by us.

###  6\. Sending a message to our support team

When you contact us through our website or by e-mail, we collect the data you have given to us in order to reply with the information you need.

We record your request and our reply in order to increase the efficiency of our business.

We keep personally identifiable information associated with your message, such as your name and email address so as to be able to track our communications with you to provide a high quality service.

###  7\. Complaining

When we receive a complaint, we record all the information you have given to us.

We use that information to resolve your complaint.

If your complaint reasonably requires us to contact some other person, we may decide to give to that other person some of the information contained in your complaint. We do this as infrequently as possible, but it is a matter for our sole discretion as to whether we do give information, and if we do, what that information is.

We may also compile statistics showing information obtained from this source to assess the level of service we provide, but not in a way that could identify you or any other person.

###  8\. Affiliate and business partner information

This is information given to us by you in your capacity as an affiliate of us or as a business partner.

It allows us to recognise visitors that you have referred to us, and to credit to you commission due for such referrals. It also includes information that allows us to transfer commission to you.

The information is not used for any other purpose.

We undertake to preserve the confidentiality of the information and of the terms of our relationship.

We expect any affiliate or partner to agree to reciprocate this policy.

##  Use of information we collect through automated systems when you visit our website

###  9\. Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer's hard drive by your web browser when you visit a website. They allow information gathered on one web page to be stored until it is needed for use on another, allowing a website to provide you with a personalised experience, and the website owner with statistics about how you use the website so that it can be improved.

Some cookies may last for a defined period of time, such as one day or until you close your browser. Others last indefinitely.

Our website uses third party cookies. They are placed by software that operates on our servers, and by software operated by third parties whose services we use.

An example is that we use Google Analytics to measure the performance of our website.

We may use the information we obtain from your use of our cookies for the following purposes:

to improve the website’s usability;

to analyse your use of our website;

to provide certain interactive functionality, such as remembering your answers to previous questions on a multi-page questionnaire.

Most of browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies, and to delete ones that have been placed on your computer.

If you do not want us to use cookies, you may disable their use in your browser. However, if you do so then please note that you may not be able to use all the features on our website.

##  Disclosure and sharing of your information

###  10\. Information we obtain from third parties

Although we do not disclose your personal information to any third party (except as set out in this notice), we sometimes receive data that is indirectly made up from your personal information from third parties whose services we use.

No such information is personally identifiable to you.

###  11\. Credit reference

To assist in combating fraud, we share information with credit reference agencies, so far as it relates to clients or customers who instruct their credit card issuer to cancel payment to us without having first provided an acceptable reason to us and given us the opportunity to refund their money.

###  12\. Data may be processed outside the European Union

Our websites are hosted in UK

We may also use outsourced services in countries outside the European Union from time to time in other aspects of our business.

Accordingly data obtained within the UK or any other country could be processed outside the European Union.

##  Access to your own information

###  13\. Access to your personal information

**13.1**    At any time you may review or update personally identifiable information that we hold about you, by signing in to your account on our website.

**13.2**    To obtain a copy of any information that is not provided on our website you may send us a request at [support@netlawman.co.uk](mailto:support@netlawman.co.uk)

**13.3**    After receiving the request, we will tell you when we expect to provide you with the information, and whether we require any fee for providing it to you.

###  14\. Removal of your information

If you wish us to remove personally identifiable information from our website, you may contact us at [support@netlawman.co.uk](mailto:support@netlawman.co.uk).

This may limit the service we can provide to you.

###  15\. Verification of your information

When we receive any request to access, edit or delete personal identifiable information we shall first take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access or otherwise taking any action. This is important to safeguard your information.

##  Other matters

###  16\. Use of site by children

**16.1**    We do not sell products or provide services for purchase by children, nor do we market to children.

**16.2**    If you are under 18, you may use our website only with consent from a parent or guardian

###  17\. How you can complain

**17.1**    If you are not happy with our privacy policy or if you have any complaint then you should tell us by email. Our address is [support@netlawman.co.uk](mailto:support@netlawman.co.uk).

**17.2**    If a dispute is not settled then we hope you will agree to attempt to resolve it by engaging in good faith with us in a process of mediation or arbitration.

**17.3**    If you are in any way dissatisfied about how we process your personal information, you have a right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner's Office. This can be done at <https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/>

###  18\. Retention period for personal data

Except as otherwise mentioned in this privacy notice, we keep your personal information only for as long as required by us:

**18.1**    to provide you with the services you have requested;

**18.2**    to comply with other law, including for the period demanded by our tax authorities;

**18.3**    to support a claim or defence in court.    

###  19\. Compliance with the law

Our privacy policy has been compiled so as to comply with the law of every country or legal jurisdiction in which we aim to do business. If you think it fails to satisfy the law of your jurisdiction, we should like to hear from you.

However, ultimately it is your choice as to whether you wish to use our website.

###  20\. Review of this privacy policy

We may update this privacy notice from time to time as necessary. The terms that apply to you are those posted here on our website on the day you use our website. We advise you to print a copy for your records.

If you have any question regarding our privacy policy, please [contact us](https://www.netlawman.co.uk/contact).
